Kristopher Fine

Electrical Construction Trades Inspector - Philadelphia Water Department

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Kristopher-Fine/234d5c90bc3c2091

Licensed and certified Master Electrician in the State of Pennsylvania. Have over fifteen years' experience in the

areas of electrical inspection, repair and installation in the residential, commercial and industrial electrical environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Electrical Construction Trades Inspector

Philadelphia Water Department - Philadelphia, PA - February 2008 to Present

Examines electrical wiring systems and components to check for fire and other hazards; sight checks electrical wiring, equipment and appliances; investigates wiring for proper grounding installation and insulation; inspects circuits for proper fuse and wire sizing; inspects receptacles, switches and light fixtures; checks the adequacy of power source for the emergency lighting systems; audits the activities of independent electrical inspection firms to

assure that their inspections are being made properly and that all electrical code requirements are being met; explains and interprets pertinent sections of the electrical code and related regulations and ordinances to electricians, contractors. Coordinates with contractors to determine when electrical work is going to be performed; visit job sites to inspect the and insure that it is being done according to the electrical code, approved

plans and specifications; discuss changes in plans and specifications with contractor; discuss major deviations in plans and specifications with Electrical Design and Engineer; insures that work is completed in conformance with

acceptable trade practices.

Inspect the installation, overhaul or repair of electrical equipment such as pumps, compressors,

switchgear, load control equipment, surveillance systems, air conditioning, lighting and power equipment; inspect the installation or renovations of electrical systems at public facilities; test equipment; observe test of equipment

conduct by consultants; meet with contractors and manufactures to discuss warranties and coordinate inspection

work.

Philadelphia Water Department (Waste Water Plant)

Industrial Plant Electrician

motor control centers - June 2003 to February 2008

2

Maintain, troubleshoot, install and repair 13.2 kv switchgear; 4160 volt switchgear; switchgear charging equipment and batteries; dry transformers; motor control centers; 208 / 480 volt circuit breaker; single and three

phase motors such as those used to run pumps, compressors and valves; troubleshoot and repair adjustable

frequency drives; break apart end bells and rotor; cleans, bake and test stator; remove and replace worn bearings and brushes; disassembles starters; clean contacts, relay timers and potentiometers; calibrates trip settings on circuit breakers and overload relays; repair limit switches, pushbutton.

Utilizes CRT terminals to assist in diagnosing system problems; troubleshoot, repair and install multiplexers, PLC, power systems (UPS) and electronic equipment.

Repair, Maintain and installed lighting systems; installed high pressure sodium high mast lighting systems; repair and maintain electrical inputs and outputs powered emergency generators; install and repair alarm systems.

Industrial Plant Electrician

Aluminum Shapes, LLC - May 1999 to June 2003

Maintain, troubleshoot, install and repair; 4160 volt switchgear; switchgear charging equipment and batteries; dry transformers; motor control centers; 208/ 480 volt circuit breaker; single and three phase motors such as those used to run pumps, compressors and valves; troubleshoot and repair adjustable frequency drives; break apart end bells and rotor; cleans bake and test stator; remove and replace worn bearings and brushes; disassembles starters; clean contacts, relay timers and potentiometers; calibrates trip settings on circuit breakers and overload relays; repair limit switches, pushbutton.

Utilizes CRT terminals to assist in diagnosing system problems; troubleshoot, repair and install multiplexers, PLC, power systems (UPS) and electronic equipment. Repair, maintain and installed lighting systems;

installed high pressure sodium high mast lighting systems; repair and maintain electrical inputs and outputs on emergency generators; install and repair alarm systems.

Electrician

Philadelphia Tramrail Company - Philadelphia, PA - September 1996 to May 1999

Install wire and conduit on overhead cranes; bend conduit; install single and three phase 208/480 volt squirrel cage motors, wound rotor motors; fabricate control and power panels; install and programmed variable frequency

drives; work from power and control distribution schematics and diagrams; troubleshooting and repairing overhead cranes electrical system; install festoon cable and buss bars; install pushbutton pendants and radio controls.

EDUCATION

Diploma in Commercial and Industrial

CHI Institute - Southampton, PA